sauropol.com 2014-02-08

# Create a Free Website | Sauropol: Privacy Policy

**Last Updated 29.04.2008**

Your privacy on the Internet is ultimately important to us. Because we gather certain types of information about our users, we feel you should fully understand our policy and the terms and conditions surrounding the capture and use of that information. This privacy statement discloses what information we gather and how we use it.

## What information we collect

### Website visitors

We collect non-personal information through aggregated tracking information derived mainly by page views throughout our sites. This information is of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. We may automatically record information on our server logs from your browser, including your IP address, cookies, and the pages you request, but we do not use such information to identify our visitors. Our purpose in collecting aggregated information is to improve the content of our website and services.

We may collect any information that you enter on any of our web sites or give us in any other way in order to contact you about Sauropol Services. We may request that you fill out a form in which we ask for information such as your name, email address, or any other. We only use this information to contact you in order to provide information about Sauropol services and answer any questions that you may have.

### Registered Users

When you register for any of the Sauropol Services we collect only the minimum amount of personal information that is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the service.

The amount and type of information we gather from registered users depends on the nature of the interaction. We ask visitors who sign up for a Sauropol website service to provide a username and email address. When you apply for premium services, we ask that you provide us with additional information, such as your name and address, telephone number, payment information if applicable (e.g., credit card number, credit card expiration date and billing address) and any other information.

We may occasionally conduct user surveys to better target our content to our audience. We may share the aggregated demographic information in these surveys with our sponsors, advertisers and partners. We never share any of this information about specific individuals with any third party.

We do not disclose your personal information other than as described below. All visitors can always refuse to supply personal information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from using full range of Sauropol services.

## How we use information we gather

We use your information on an aggregated basis, we statistically analyze site usage to improve our services and better understand your needs.

We may share aggregate information about our members with third parties, such as advertisers or partners, for marketing and promotional purposes. Under no circumstances we do not disclose any information about an individual user to a third party partner.

We may use any information voluntarily given by our users to provide interactive or personalized elements on our websites or to better prepare future content based on the interests of our users.

We may use the information we collect to send out newsletters to subscribers about important functionality changes of the Sauropol Services, special offers (including promotion of our product or third party products) which we think you will find valuable. You may choose not to receive messages from us by following the opt-out instructions. 

For fulfilling Sauropol subscription-based services we use the information we collect to process payments, confirm renewal charges or payments to your account, administer your account and the like. 

## How we use cookies

We may place a text file called a "cookie" in the browser files of your computer. The cookie itself does not contain personal information although it will enable us to relate your use of this site to information that you have specifically and knowingly provided. The only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. A cookie can't read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. 

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies or notify you when a cookie is set. 

If you reject all cookies it may prevent you from taking full advantage of our website and services.

## Information Disclosure

We do not disclosure information about individual users with any third party, except to comply with applicable law or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public or protect our rights.

## Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. However, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. We make every effort to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. 

Your Sauropol account is password-protected so in addition to those partners or agents who you authorize to provide you services, only you and those you designate can access it and view the member information relevant to your account. Ultimately, you are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and any account information. Remember to log out of your Sauropol account and close your browser window when you are done. This ensures that others cannot access your personal information if your computer is accessible to others. 

In some areas, we use a secure connection - industry-standard SSL-encryption - to protect data transmissions, eg when collecting personal financial information from you. However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed by breach of such firewalls and secure server software.

## Information Relating to Children

Sauropol is not intended for use by children under the age of 13. Consistent with the Federal Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), we will never knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without requesting parental consent.

## Controlling your personal information

  * You can edit your Sauropol account information at any time.
  * You can choose not to receive our electronic newsletters.
  * You can request to deactivate your account. However, please note that some personal information may remain in our records to the extent necessary to protect our legal interests or document compliance with regulatory requirements.

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.
